All right, everybody. Welcome back to
the number one podcast in the world.
Your favorite podcast. Your podcaster's
favorite podcast. Yes, it's the All-In
podcast. The Core Four, the Fantastic
Four, the original Quartet is here.
David Freeberg, hot off of his deep
state conspiracy interview with Eric
Weinstein.
Amazing. You did a little run to DC.
Great episode, Freeberg.
>> It was fun. Eric is one of a kind. I saw
Katzios, too. kind of two sides of the
coin of science in America was the basis
of those two interviews. They were fun.
>> Who is Eric Weinstein? He's a scientist
who works with Peter Teal from Harvard.
Has done some really capital.
>> Yeah. And he um he had a podcast for a
hot minute. He is a heterodox thinker in
science.
>> What is his heterodoxical thought about
science? There's all these things that
everyone takes as fundamental premises
in modern physics like the string theory
as an example and he thought it was
and called it out as
So he's been kind of outcast in the
scientific communities.
>> It is right? And so he's made
this case and he's proposed alternative
theories that kind of create a grand
unification theory of physics. And then
he's been outcast by the scientific
community and people say that he's a
quack and he's and he's talked
about UFOs and he's talked about Jeffrey
Epstein and people kind of say well this
guy's fringe or they use these different
terms to chastise him and over time you
know the point is similar to what Katios
has said like so much of science has
kind of followed this sheeplike
mentality where everyone has to line up
agree to the same general theory or you
get outcast you don't get grant funding
you don't get tenure you don't jobs, you
don't get invited to do lectures, you
have to follow the mainstream in science
or you're outcasts. And it used to be
that all about
>> I know, but it's very rational to say
until string theory is proved, it's
unproved. And so if you want to use the
adjective that's fine. It'll
probably offend some people, but he's
more right on the substance of what he's
saying than he is wrong. It's unproved,
right? It's like Jay Bodacharia being
like, "Hey, you know, CO may have come
from a lab leak." And when people were
saying this, they were they were told
you were creating conspiracy theories.
You were pushing misinformation when
there is no misinformation. If there's
no absolute truth that you're talking
about, it's theory. Everyone was
starting with theory on where the COVID
came from.
>> You're talking about a level of
corruption in a very narrow specific
realm of science, which is the funding
and grant approval apparatus that
>> and getting tenure and getting
professorships. And so if you don't
follow the voting, the methods, the
theory, if you don't follow the
mainstream, you're outcast. By the way,
I buy that. I don't I don't know Eric.
>> This is what has led to stagnation in
science in America because if you're not
part of the mainstream, you get
excluded. And because everyone has to
now think in the same way, you don't
have heterodox thinking. You don't have
outside of the scope thinking, which
means we're not pushing the envelope and
discovering new things anymore. And
that's a very kind of pointed issue
right now. That's why I went and talked
to Kratos said differently. There's
probably a lot of incrementalism in 2026
that didn't exist in 1926. Totally. It's
exactly right. Think about the general
theory of relativity being published. It
was completely outlandish. But people
still studied it, assessed it. They
didn't discredit it and say, "Oh, you're
an idiot." And if you're thinking about
this general theory of relativity is
being real, you're a That's what
goes on today in science where if you
say stuff that's too far outside of the
realm of the standard approach to
things, you're you're chastised. You're
outcast. You're excluded. Do you guys
see the uh Olympics? You see the robot
Olympics sacks? Check this out.
>> I did see it. Yeah. This is pretty
crazy. They had these uh Olympics in
China and
>> oh my god, they copied how Freeberg
actually runs there. Look at that. Look
at that. Yes, that is definitely a
Freeberg sprint.
>> The Freeberg sprint.
>> Doing the Freeberg sprint. Look at this
one. He backs up and then boom.
>> That's my sprint. That's like me skiing
right there.
>> Yeah. Look. And there's Jason
setting records at 42. This is Jason
right here.
>> Here's Jason Yeah. with his shirt
off at the poker game. Really great. Put
your shirt back on. you know, I I
was thinking about this, Sachs. You know
what I realized? I think you're 100%
right about the PR. And I realize that
the Chinese, the CCP is brilliant at PR.
Look what they did. They got a bunch of
Chinese people to fill a stadium and
cheer for AI and robotics. They're
cheering for it. They're rooting for it.
And then we got Daario saying all jobs
are over. We're going to be the last
company in the world and it's the end of
days. I get back on Dario. We're not
talking about Dario this week. We're not
talking about Dario this week.
>> Your grand unifying theory is that in a
country of a billion people, they
couldn't find 4,000 to show up to watch
a bunch of robots run around a track.
Are you really surprises that unifying
theory?
>> It is true that China is much more
optimistic about AI than we are. AI
optimism in China is over 80%. meaning
they pull on the question, do you think
AI will be more beneficial than harmful?
Over 80% of Chinese people say yes. In
the US, that number is in like 30%.
>> So, I've been saying for a while that
the US is ahead of China in every
category except one, which is optimism.
And that is the biggest risk to us
winning this AI race against China is
doing something that will shoot
ourselves in the foot because we're so
pessimistic about what AI might do.
>> I think it's all scops. They're making
you feel. You see that? Show this the
the robot blowing up at 16 seconds,
Nick. This is all stage. It's a scops.
This is a scops. They make you feel bad
for the robots. You They make you cheer
for them. This is going to be like a
major thing.
>> No, it's the red robot. The funniest
thing was when the red robot lost his
legs, there was like a couple tweets
that I thought were hilarious. Like one
guy was like, "Oh my god, he tore his
HDMI, his CPU."
And then and then and then the second
one which is not funny because I know
Christian McCaffrey and he's a great
guy. He's like Christian McCaffrey in
week three and you just see the entire
leg just snap off. Very very mean.
Congratulations to the CCP. By the way,
Optimus, have you got has have you guys
seen the latest Optimus videos from Elon
by chance? Has he shown any of you guys?
>> Haven't seen it.
>> He's not publishing publicly. I saw the
latest Optimus.
>> It would win half of these things
already. I You guys see it? It's He's
making sick progress and he's not
showing it publicly, but I saw it
>> without the sparks coming out of its
midsection.
>> No sparks, but I I saw a video
>> that I said to him, I said, "Is this CGI
or is this real?" And he said, "No, this
is real. They just sent it to me this
morning." And it's like, "Whoa, Optimus
will be the bestselling,
I think, product."
>> Yeah. You know, the hard part, as I
understand it, with these robots is you
can train them to do a specific action
like run in that race or jump or
whatever. But the hard part is when they
encounter a condition that they weren't
programmed to expect and specifically
when they have to interact with
something in the physical world, that's
when it gets tricky, right? Can they do
the whole folding laundry or pick
something up without breaking it or
dropping it or whatever? And
specifically something that they weren't
taught to do, you know,
>> that's where it gets tricky
>> there. Yeah. The fidelity of the Optimus
is and its ability to do novel things.
You kind of nailed it. I don't want to
say anymore. You've been playing with
Grockbot though, right, Sax?
>> Yeah. Oh, yeah.
>> You got you got Grockbot shoted. You've
been Grockbot maxing.
>> I just reached my Grockbot usage limit
and have to upgrade. So
>> 200 bucks.
>> I've been Yeah. It's been really
interesting actually.
>> Yeah. What? It just does what you tell
it to do, right? Like it just gets it
done.
>> Yeah. What's great about Grockbot is
that it's always on. it's in the cloud.
You set up your agents and then they can
keep working even when your computer is
off or it goes to sleep. The other, you
know, agent harnesses that were kind of
doing this or like OpenClaw or Hermes,
they were just on your desktop. So if
your computer went to sleep, they would
stop. You have to do all these Mac minis
and also they were like very hard to
use, very power, super complicated.
>> This is like by far the easiest. It's
still a lot of work to get it set up
working right perfectly or whatever, but
it's fun and it's the easiest it's ever
been and you can really see where it's
all going.
>> Yeah, it's it's pretty amazing. I told
him he should make it multiplayer mode.
So like you can put two agents in the
same room, but then being able to put
two people from your team in the same
room and then you know having humans in
the loop, it it's going to go
>> such a good idea. That will make this
thing go so freaking viral.
>> Yes. if you can just add because then
you know what's what's cool about the
agents is you actually have an agent
swarm. You actually have lots of
different agents performing different
tasks and they get good at different
things. You know some people ask why
don't you just have one agent? It turns
out that if you have multiple agents
then the agents develop more context and
expertise
>> so they get more specific. But yeah, you
could then use each of those agents as a
channel and invite people to it and then
they participate in that
>> and then they add another person. Yeah,
it's
>> Yeah, then it could get very very viral.
>> Yeah, it's a great product. All right,
let's get to work. We got a lot going
on. Nvidia just had a record setting
earnings report. I mean, they blew the
doors off this and uh also uh we'll talk
a little bit about Salesforce also
coming back and the SAS apocalypse
ending stock was up Nvidia's that is 9%
on huge numbers and even huger guidance
96.2 2 billion in revenue in the
quarter. Chimoth up 106% year-over-year,
more than double. Wall Street's
expectation was 92 billion. They guided
for 70% growth next year. That is well
above what Wall Street was expecting at
45%. So, let that sink in. The number
people are going crazy over 60 billion
in net profit. That is the most
profitable core business quarter of any
public company ever. Google and Amazon,
they've had higher one-off quarters, uh,
obviously. Here's your chart. Nvidia net
income and revenue quarterly, just
blowing the doors off of it. Stock is
up. It's reaching its all-time high
again, getting close.
Heading into earnings, Nvidia was only
up 12% year to date, on par with the S&P
500, but they were lagging the broader
chip index. I guess the headwind Chamath
is that people believe there's
competition coming. We'll talk about
that. Nvidia is the world's most
valuable company. 5.5 trillion. Poly
Market says 79% chance. Here's your Poly
Market, our great partner, Poly Market.
79% chance Nvidia ends the year as
number one, 6.3 million in volume. In
other news, Salesforce up over 20% on
Thursday after they also reported a big
quarter. Revenue up 11.3 billion 11%
year-over-year. uh that was in line with
expectations, but they uh beated their
adjusted EPS by 80% 590 versus $327.
They got a big jump because they are
major investors in Anthropic. They
raised their full year guidance to 46
billion.
You called it let's give Chimath his
victory fap. Here he goes, the victory
fap. The lap Chimath on May 15.
>> What's your take on this? You've been
pretty critical of the SAS space in
previous episodes.
>> I think the high end of the market where
Mark operates, where the large monoliths
operate is quite safe. What people are
finding is, hey, hold on a second. This
is a lot harder than we thought. It's
not like boop boop boop, put in a prompt
and beep boop, it all works. It's not
how it works. I think we're a little
oversold. Now, I think this
consolidation and the rerating can
happen in the opposite direction. So,
what is the opposite trade? The opposite
trade is who has constructive net dollar
retention, who has negative churn that's
been really predictable, which is a way
of saying who has the best
relationships. Those guys, I think, are
positioned to crush.
>> All right, there you have it, Shimath.
Your thoughts on Nvidia and Salesforce
blowing the doors off of their quarterly
earnings reports.
>> There's a lot there. So maybe we'll
start with Salesforce first and then
I'll go to Nvidia because I think the
Nvidia one is actually a good segue into
talking about the national state of
finance. Um
I don't know. It was pretty obvious to
me in May that Salesforce specifically
was meaningfully oversold.
I think what I was trying to say there
and maybe I can say more precisely now
is we're getting to the end of this
second phase of AI. So if the first
phase of AI were models and think of
like a model as a brain, the second
phase of AI is harnesses, right? agents,
which is the analogous equivalent of
giving a brain a pair of eyes and hands
and a notebook for memory and a keyboard
to type things on. So, you're sort of
taking this primordial object that was
really good at Q&A and you're making it
more useful almost like an autonomous
being.
But we're starting this next phase soon.
At least I see it in the enterprises
that I work with, which is that that's
still insufficient. And what you now
need to do is make that autonomous agent
much more informed and give it context
and allow it to do a job much more
intelligently. So meaning you take a
brain, you give it arms and legs and
limbs and eyes and etc. But then you
have to train it to be a lawyer or be a
customer service rep or be a sales agent
or what have you. And to do that next
step, you need a ton of contextual
information. And so the people that
control that today, the large systems of
record,
what I said before and what I'll double
down on now is that those guys hold an
incredibly special place in the
ecosystem if they do it right. And I
think what you're seeing is Mark is
finding a way to play well with the
models, support harnesses, but also
build his own, and now start to push
into this next phase.
And I think that's why his net dollar
retention is strong. That's why his
revenue is strong. That's why he's
guiding up. And that's why the stocks
ripped. I think was it like up 43% since
I said it had bottomed. I mean it took a
>> Yeah, it was up 20% today just on that.
And Freeberg, I think you were in Were
you on CNBC or you just on the quarterly
call?
>> I went to Benny Off's office for the
earnings setup yesterday. So Daario was
there. Daario and Mark did their CNBC
bit. They set up a studio for the
earnings call on the 60th floor, you
know, where we've all had dinner up
there. And then I did the earnings call
with Mark cuz you know about a year ago
I think I mentioned this to you Chimoth
like we kind of over a weekend built a
CRM tool internally using uh cloud code
and cursor and stuff and kind of spun it
together and stood it up and we were
using it and then it's like well you got
to add this feature and you got to
change this and then account and
security and access and where's the data
repository that makes it protected and
there was a lot of kind of back and
forth on all the features we ultimately
needed to build to make it truly useful
and scalable. Meanwhile, we've got
competing interests at our company on
where we can build software that's
unique to our company like plant
breeding software which is what we do as
kind of our unique advantage as a
company is plant breeding. So, how do we
build a better breeding technology
platform? How do we build software that
gives the the people in the lab and in
the greenhouse and the breeders tools?
And so we started building all these
internal tools and eventually realized
our time, our efforts, our energy is
better spent building the workflows that
are unique and create value for our
organization uniquely versus recreating
a bunch of software that other people
have already made. Where's your best
ROI, your best return on time spent and
your best return on dollars spent? And
it's not on rebuilding a communications
tool like Slack or a messaging tool like
Gmail or a CRM tool like Salesforce.
And at the time Mark and I were talking
on the phone, he's like, you know, hey,
try Salesforce. I'll set you up. Come
on, do it. And I was like, no, no, no.
And then he's like, yes, yes, yes. And
he and he's so persistent. You guys know
Mark. He's like so persistent. He put
his like best sales guy on a text with
me and kept texting every day. Are we up
yet? Are we up yet? Are we up yet? Until
the sales guy I said, okay, go to my
office. He goes to my office. He gets
set up and we're and then we're done.
And then we realized, oh my god, this is
actually a much better way for us to do
this. So Mark asked me to come and
recount that story at the earnings call
and talk a little bit about the view on
this change. So I do think and I've
shared this in the past I think the
horizontal platform companies these
tools that are horizontal CRM works
across many different verticals industry
verticals and Gmail works across many
industry verticals and Slack and so on.
Excel no one's going to go rebuild
Excel. The the real value is in the the
software that's unique for your
vertical. That's where AI plays a role
in building custom workflows and custom
software. And so I think that's kind of
how I view this, the real SAS
apocalypse. It's more of a vertical SAS
apocalypse, which is software that's
designed for just one vertical%.
>> Um, and that's where I think things get
blown up.
>> I totally agree with you.
>> A platform like Salesfor.
>> I totally agree with you. I totally
agree with you,
>> Sax. Let's talk about Mark Beni off. He
is just an incredible salesperson who
just fought through the SAS apocalypse
and then figured out a way out of being
put in the bucket of SAS roadkill and
then just massively um integrating AI
into the platform. Maybe you you've
known him for a long time. Maybe you
could talk about him as an executive and
what we can learn from what he just did
in terms of going from in the market's
mind roadkill to leading the pack let's
say in SAS again.
>> Well, this narrative of the SAS
apocalypse was totally overdone. I mean,
this whole SAS is dead narrative is just
getting shredded today with Salesforce
being up over 20%. You could go back and
look at some of the clips I've been
saying now for months. I do not believe
that core systems of record like CRM are
going to get ripped and replaced with
something vibe coded. I've been saying
that for a long time. Enterprises want
certainty. They have compliance. They
want professionally managed software
that's been running and debugged for
years. I mean, just think about all the
bug reports that have been filed against
Salesforce for over 20 years, right? And
that's the hard part to get right. I
mean, when I play with all these agents
and AI, you're dealing with something
that's probabistic and there's so many
edge cases. When you're dealing with a
core system of record, you just want to
know that it works. And the expense of
it is low enough that you just don't
want to basically jeopardize one of your
core systems by ripping it out and
replacing it with something built
in-house in a kind of DIY way. So, I I
just think this whole SAS apocalypse
narrative was overplayed. Now, at the
same time, to your point, Jason, I think
Beni off is doing all the right things
here. And you could kind of say it's a
if you can't beat them, join them type
approach, which is he made this deal
with Anthropic.
What is that deal? I mean, first of all,
he's going to be offering Anthropics
models inside of Salesforce. More
importantly, I think this is really the
critical thing. He is integrating
Salesforce into Claude. He's willing to
allow Claude to be the front end to have
the sort of the primary user
relationship. and Claude is now going to
be able to access all of the data in
Salesforce and all of the workflows, all
the actions that a user can take. So, in
other words, Beni off here is willing to
risk disintermediation
in order to ride this AI wave because he
knows it's what the customer ultimately
wants. You know, you don't want to go
into Salesforce or any SAS application
to write your agents. you want to create
agents in the AI program that you're
using and you want those agents to be
able to run across all of your SAS
platforms. So he's willing to again to
give up a big piece of the user
relationship in order to make himself
more relevant. Now why is this
ultimately good for his business and not
bad is because like I said I still think
that you need systems of record. You
need the AI agents to basically go to
those systems get the data from a
canonical source of truth. You just
don't want there to be any probabilistic
variability around that and you want AI
agents to be able to write back to those
systems and you want to be able to write
back to those workflows. So what's
happening here is that it's not a rip
and replace. They're layers are getting
built, right? You've got the database
layer, then you've got applications and
workflows and then you've got agents and
then you've kind of got the the AI uh
user interface. And Betty off is saying
that the AI is now the user interface.
He's basically acknowledging that he's
leaning into it. Now, here's the thing.
I talked to him this morning actually
and and a point he brought up with me
that I think is underestimated
is that he says there's a lot of trap
value in Salesforce. Meaning, we know
it's got this incredibly broadrich
platform with tons of functionality. The
average user is never going to find all
those things, but the agent will. So,
think about all the cases where now the
agent is going to go to the user and
say, "Hey, I just saw that there are
these actions you could take in
Salesforce that seem to line up with
what you're telling me to do. Do you
want me to do this?" And the user is
going to say, "Yes,
>> modify Salesforce as the system of
record." Yes, sir.
>> Yes. Exactly. Because now think about
the agent as a power user of Salesforce
that knows how to use Salesforce
perfectly. You don't necessarily need to
hire this like team of highly priced
consultants to figure out Salesforce.
The agent knows how to do it. So it can
unlock the full value of Salesforce and
all these actions. And then after you
develop trust in your agent, you the
user are just going to click the always
allow button and now the agent can
basically tap the full capabilities of
Salesforce. So I mean that's where this
is headed. But now it raises the
question, okay, so how do SAS
applications play into this AI and agent
wave? You have to have great APIs and
you have to have a great CLI, the
command line interface, which is how the
agents are going to relate to the SAS
tools. I think in the past, the way that
most SAS products thought, they spent a
lot of time on their user interface. And
now they really got to think about the
agent interface, not just user
interface. You have to build the best
agent interface. And you've got to, I
think, relax the idea that you're going
to fully control the customer
relationship. You have to think of
agents created by the AI companies as
being an extension of your platform and
not feel threatened that you're losing
the customer relationship. If you can do
all those things and become a source of
truth and a system of record, then
you've got a big opportunity. I I got to
say he's like one of the most
underestimated and underappreciated
product and sales executives in our
industry because I was talking to him
when we were at Davos Sachs about Slack
and he was like tell me about what
you're doing and I was like listen you
have all my data I can't get my data my
team wants to move off Slack they want
to use this open source product
specifically so I can get all this
information he again to your point
freeberg put me on with the sales team
and now I have complete god access to
our Slack Slack and they built a product
called Slack today which they've been
slowly rolling out and it does the
promise of OpenClaw and what Sam did by
buying out the founder of OpenClaw right
after he bought OpenClaw's founder Peter
and he started working at uh Open AI
just openclaw just faded like no more
innovation and I'm not trying to say
this to say Sam did something nefarious
or that Open Claw is you know terrible
or anything but they just lost their
edge.
And now the version of Slack today is
like a seven out of 10 and it's getting
like 10% better every couple of weeks
I'm noticing. So he's going to do a
parallel link sacks. He's going to have
his own agents and he's going to let you
come in with your agents. His agents
might be a little bit behind but you're
also going to get those agents for free
inside of Salesforce. It's like a a two
ways to win, you I mean, look, I think I
think that SAS products can offer their
own agents and they can offer their own
AI and co-pilots and all that, but I
think the reality is is that most of the
action with agents is going to happen
outside those products and simply want
to interact with those products and
basically get the data from them, use
them as the system of record, as the
source of truth and then write actions
back to them when appropriate. And I
just think that founders should lean
into that trend instead of fighting it
because if you fight to stay in control
and say that only our agents are the way
to interact with our system then people
will just move to they'll leave.
>> So are you are you long vertical SAS or
are you short it like Freeberg and I
are.
>> I think it's specific to the company and
what its modes are and how good a system
of record is and all those things.
>> Well is no I don't think vertical SAS
has a system of record. I don't think
that's what they do. I think their
workflows this is the key point where
these horizontal monolithic companies
like Salesforce
are just unique workday Oracle with
respect to their GL it's just very
difficult SAP IFS it's very difficult to
see a path where you can replicate these
businesses and they become the
repository and the single source of
truth as you said but vertical SAS is
workflows and it's a process and I just
wonder what survives
>> well I look I think it's a it's a good
question and I think It's case by case,
but look, just a few months ago,
everyone was saying that horizontal SAS
wasn't going to survive. And one of
Liupold's major positions in that fund
was to short all these SAS products,
including Salesforce. And what we've
seen is that has turned out to be wrong
or totally over.
>> To be to be fair, I don't know that he
understood the difference between
vertical and horizontal SAS because that
was a funding short problem, meaning he
had to go to the big stocks in order to
be able to short enough to be able to
get the leverage that he wanted. So, I
think he may have just worked backwards
from his own mental narrative to make it
all sound correct, but I suspect it was
a leverage trap where he's like, I need
to be really massively net long these
other names. And his prime broker is
like, well, you got to find shorts,
liquid shorts, and he's like, okay,
Adobe and Salesforce.
>> Well, but look, I mean, to be fair, I
think that was the dominant narrative as
of just a few months ago with SAS
Apocalypse, and Benoff's stock was
getting hammered by the market. I mean
down 50% now it's up back 20. So I think
a lot of people were just
indiscriminately selling all SAS. And I
think that if I had to say there's like
one takeaway from the news today is that
I think simple extrapolations
of the future based on these trends
don't work out right the simple
extrapolation here was AI agents can
code therefore all software is going to
zero. That was the simplistic
extrapolation. Now what we're seeing is
no actually there are certain systems of
record that are extremely compatible and
complimentary to AI agents and if
they're positioned right by their
founders they can lean into this trend.
And by the way I think the job loss
narrative is another one of those
simplistic extrapolations. What is the
the job loss narrative is now AI can do
knowledge work therefore knowledge
workers are all going to lose their
jobs. It completely ignores the fact
that there's ways for knowledge workers
to take advantage of the tools and lean
into it. So the same way that Beni off
is taking advantage of the agent trend,
knowledge workers are taking advantage
of it and they're going to be able to
lean into it.
>> If you adopt the technology, you
survive. If you don't, you die. I mean,
it's pretty pretty straightforward. I
just wanted to also point out with
Nvidia's incredible results. Two things
that happen very quietly. Um, and Jensen
is clearly open- source maxing now. He
bought Hugging Face for 12 billion. And
he did like one of these aqua hire deals
with Poolside for 6 billion total, about
20 billion in um 20 billion in
acquisitions, which is far less than 1%
of the market cap of Nvidia. And thank
God you can do M&A again in this
country. But he's now owning the
distribution layer for open-source. Uh
if you don't know Poolside, they make
the uh coding model Laguna. So now
Nvidia has the place where developers
and hackers go to figure out which open
>> Sorry. Sorry. I don't I don't think
that's what went over. My understanding
is that the because Jason Warner tweeted
this morning about a new model drop. I I
I was confused by this because I they
there could be two things that they're
buying. the 100 engineers that are going
over to Nvidia, they could be working on
uh what poolside has, which is
effectively a version of cursor
and cloud code that runs, you know, on
prem that runs in
>> open source open weight.
>> No, then they also have a model. What
I'm saying is they have a model and then
they also have this agent harness that
that you can direct coding. So, I don't
it wasn't clear to me in the
announcement. I didn't read it
carefully. Yeah.
>> What it is that they bought.
>> I think we're kind of burying the lead
here by the way. It's like, look,
they're reportedly doing these deals
with Poolside and Hugging Face, and
those are big open source acquisitions
if the reporting is true. But look, here
is the the lead today, I think, is that
first of all, Nvidia had a blowout
quarter doing over 100% year-over-year.
>> A billion a day in revenue now.
>> Yeah. Almost 100 billion in revenue just
for the quarter. $60 billion of profit.
75% gross margins. I mean, excluding
one-off items, this was the most profit
ever generated by a company in history.
J, let me just underscore what you said
in the intro. Yeah.
>> Which is really I think the reason why
the stock is up 8% today is not just the
great quarter, but the fact that they
guided to 70% growth next year, whereas
the street was only expecting around
45%. So that's pretty amazing. And that
70% number would have been higher, but
they said they were supply constraint.
>> Yes.
>> So, you know, what what is the takeaway?
I think for the larger market here, it
is that the AI boom is continuing. The
other narrative that's getting shredded
today is that this AI capex is a bubble.
It's basically going to end very soon.
And what Nvidia is basically saying with
its numbers and forecasts is actually
this AI capex is going to continue well
into the future. It's got real legs. And
the amazing thing is that after these
numbers, even despite the 8% bump,
Nvidia is only trading at 12 times
earnings.
>> Yes. And that reason is people think
that competition obviously Cerebras and
the point I was going to make earlier. I
think Jensen is going all in on open
source based on these two acquisitions,
Hugging Face and Poolside. And I think
Sam Alman poked the tiger. If you look
at what he did, he had done that huge
hundred billion dollar deal with Nvidia
back in 2025 and then he announced the
AMD deal and Jensen was clearly not
pleased about that and he talked about
right after Sam kind of did this
announcement that he's going to make his
own inference chips
>> jalapeno
>> jalapeno and that he was going to do the
deal with AMD then Jensen came out was
like well by the way we don't actually
have to do these investments in open AI
and I think he's speedr runninging open
source and you're going to be able to
buy from Nvidia next year just your
entire stack. He's going for it. He is
going to own open source. And that is a
really interesting moment in time for us
to look at cuz we were sitting here 6
months ago, 12 months ago. Oh, open
source would never catch up. He's doing
an open-source self-driving project and
now he owns Hugging Face, the leading
open-source indexer where everybody goes
to try the new models. I think this is a
this is actually the huge story. I think
the generalized takeaway should be that
you're going to see all of these
businesses converge
>> and they're all going to be competing
with each other in every which way
possible. So this idea that you have
this very delineated separation of
customer and supplier I think is melting
away. Nvidia still relies meaningfully
on the hyperscalers for their revenue. I
think it was $24 billion in the quarter,
but they now have built up a Neocloud
business that was equivalent, which is
incredible, right?
>> Yes.
>> And I think what you're going to see is
as more people try to compete with them.
So now your customers, the hyperscalers,
are saying, "We're going to spin our own
silicon." It's completely appropriate
for NVIDIA to say, "Well, we're going to
spin our own models." They do that. And
then you're going to see them go up the
stack and host the model. then you're
going to see them supply APIs and supply
inference and they're going to be a
cloud provider. And so to your point,
Jason, I think the right way to think
about it is in business 1.0, it's like
you used to be like a capex business,
right? And people would say, "Okay,
what's your return on investment?" Or
you'd be a software business and you're
like, "Okay, what's your opex, right?
And what's your return on investment?"
It's all melting together. Every
company's going to do everything. You're
going to look at these big companies in
five years. They're all going to have
their own cloud. They're all going to
have their own models. They're all going
to have their own silicon. They're all
going to have their own data centers.
Soup to nuts. They're going to go top to
bottom. And then it's going to be about
which is better. And that I think is
actually better for the broader
ecosystem. It's better for all of us.
>> Absolutely. All right, let's keep moving
through the docket. Besson's new bond
strategy got criticized by his mentor
Stan Ducken Miller. Last week, 30-year
Treasury hit a 19-year high, 5.3%.
You've been talking about this a whole
bunch, Freeberg, so I'm interested to
get your take on it. Uh, in response,
Besson doubled the Treasury Department's
elongated bond buybacks from 2 billion
to 4 billion on August 19th. CNBC
reported Besson is considering ramping
up bond buying and uh Fox Business that
said he wants to put the fear of God
into traders that are shorting longdated
bonds. So, a lot of interventionism
going on here. Stan Ducken Miller,
Besson's former mentor, published an
op-ed in the Wall Street Journal
opposing his plan. His main point was
Bessent is wrong for trying to
manipulate prices rather than fixing the
core reason yields are rising. America
has a spending problem. We've talked
about it over and over here. $40
trillion. No more Doge. No more cutting
costs. And obviously we got a war that's
quite expensive every 5 months.
Freeberg, I think you said last episode,
we add a trillion. So we're adding 2.5
trillion a year. We'll add 10 trillion
during this second uh Trump term. your
thoughts on what's going on here
Freeberg in terms of the bond market and
Bessant and Duck and Miller going back
and forth. Chimath, you and I can also
talk about using AI to write pieces,
write your pieces. Yeah,
>> I'll start with the relationship as you
highlighted. Bessent and Den Miller
worked closely together and are close
and respect each other and Kevin Walsh
in a similar position. He was working
with Dereken Miller the last number of
years in his office every day. They're
extremely close. This is a triumvirate
that I don't think in history you've had
three people who are so close in these
positions. One leading in kind of market
activity with drug, one running
Treasury, and the other one running the
Fed. It's it's pretty unprecedented
to have this sort of closeness
in those positions. And you know, I
think
>> what's that? Yeah. Right.
>> Caesar. There's
>> you called it a triumphirate.
>> The triumphirate.
>> Who's Caesar? Who's Pompy? And who's
Cassus?
>> I'm going to leave that to them to
debate. But if you pull up the yield
curve from uh COVID era, I think it's
worth just taking a look at the Treasury
yield curve. So, this shows depending on
the duration, is it a one month or a
30-year Treasury bond? So, across that
whole time duration, what's the yield?
You know, how much does the federal
government have to pay in interest to
get people to loan them money for that
duration? And so this is uh right around
co era kind of 2020. You can see that
because interest rates were low and the
inflationary effects of stimulus that
came about during co had not yet hit the
market we were looking at sub half a
percent sub a quarter% all the way out
to the 3year and 5year and then a slight
climb up where you could actually get
30-year treasuries at 1.7%.
Again going back in history it's always
easy to rewrite history. The federal
government should have rolled all of its
debt into 30 years at this point. But
the debt is balanced across this
Treasury curve. So let's look at where
the Treasury yield curve is today. So
this is what is the market charging the
federal government to loan it money to
pay its bills. And on the low end of the
Treasury curve, you're looking at just
under 4%. So for the federal government
to borrow money for one month, they have
to pay a 3.8% vig uh to the lenders for
that money. And if you go out the
30-year
is now at 5.2%.
So it is very expensive now to borrow
money if you're the US federal
government. And the reason is persistent
inflation. I would argue because of
excess government spending on social
programs and other things. And the big
problem at this point is the federal
government is spending so much that if
the federal government were to cut
spending aggressively, the argument and
the concern is it would hit unemployment
and it would cause a recession because
the federal government is such an
intricate part of the economy. Now
that's the argument. But it's causing
inflation and it is causing deficit
spending. So this year the deficit will
be roughly call it$ two trillion dollars
and as a result the market is saying we
are worried about the US fiscal solveny
over the long run or there's a higher
risk as a result we're going to charge
you a higher interest 5.2% on the
30-year now what does this mean for the
federal government? Well today the
federal government's average cost of
debt is 3.4%.
That's what we're paying on interest on
average on the $40 trillion of debt that
the federal government has outstanding.
For every 1% change in the interest
rate, the US government has to pay 1.25%
of GDP in excess interest each year.
1.25% of GDP
in interest each year for that 1% change
in the interest rate. And we're now
looking at a 30-year at 5.2 and a
short-term rate over four. So the
federal government has a problem because
over the next 12 months they have to
refinance $10 trillion of debt. That
debt is coming due. Those bonds are now
due. They have to pay the principal back
to the bond holders and they got to go
back to the treasury market and sell
more treasuries to borrow more money to
refinance. So the borrowing cost now is
going to climb up. And when that
borrowing cost climbs up, the federal
government's burn goes up and the fiscal
deficit goes up. So my theory and my
argument on this is there is no action
that Besson can take that's actually
going to have a meaningful effect on the
long end of the curve. We have
fundamental fiscal spending problem with
the federal government right now. And I
think that the note that Duck wrote,
whether AI wrote it or he wrote it, it
doesn't matter. The point of the note is
correct. And the note is meant to
provide cover to Bessant. He is saying
it is not Bessant's fault or Bessant's
responsibility to solve the yield curve
problem. It is Congress's
responsibility. It is the president's
responsibility. It is the responsibility
of the holders of the budget and the
accounts that should stand up and say we
are going to cut spending because if we
don't cut spending, there is going to be
a spiral which we are now going to face
over the next 12 months as we have to
refinance $10 trillion of debt. So
Bessant's doing his job as Treasury
Secretary. He's saying I'm going to
market. I'm going to buy treasuries. I'm
going to try and lower it. But he only
has maximum maximum maximum a trillion
dollars he could use to buy debt. He's
still got to go sell 10 trillion of
treasuries in the next 12 months. 10
trillion. He's got to sell. So even if
he maxed out his buying authority in the
near term, that's only a trillion of
buying and then he's got to turn around
and sell 10.
>> So the market is the market is and so D
drug's note is coverage for Bessant and
it's pointing responsibility back to
Congress, back to the president to say,
"Guys, we have to solve this deficit
problem." So, is this like kayf
performative between the two of them and
they're kind of like supporting each
other?
>> I don't think I don't think they're
allowed to talk. I don't think they do
talk. I don't think that Duck's allowed
to talk to Kevin or I don't think any of
them are allowed to talk to each other.
So, I don't think that's happening. But,
I think that Duck is sending his signal
to the market and saying, "Guys, this is
not Besson's responsibility." Got it.
>> The burden's not on his shoulder. He
can't be Atlas. He can't lift this
earth. He can't solve this problem. You
guys have to act.
>> I think it's coverage for
>> Bess. Got it. Okay. That's what I That's
what I was sort of getting at. Chimath,
what's your take here on what's going to
happen going forward? You know, we're
past 5%. Does this break? What does it
do to uh interest rate cuts and how bad
could this get if we can't get it under
control?
>> The tactical answer to your the question
that you asked before is why is he in
the market buying bonds? It's called
yield curve suppression. Meaning when
you buy bonds, you bid up the prices and
the implied yields go down, which allows
Scott to then finance at a lower
borrowing cost because then if yields
are 5.1 versus 5.3 and then now you're
issuing bonds, they're marked against
that 5.1 print versus 5.3. So it the
yield suppression is trying to help what
Freebrook talked about, which is just
this refinancing
tsunami that is coming. Okay. But look,
just just take a step back for a second.
I think the very big issue is that
Congress is ultimately responsible for
spending. Congress is completely unable
to do anything to get these budget
deficits under control.
It is consistent. It's not a Democrat
nor a Republican problem. It is a
congressional problem, meaning both
sides consistently
spend way more
than they should. So you have the debt
growing at 7% and you have GDP between,
you know, 2 and 4%. So that's a recipe
for disaster.
What Duck said in that note is you have
to cut entitlements. He's probably
right. The question is when? and who
will force the United States to confront
this issue? Who will force the United
States Congress to confront the issue?
And what he is saying is the bond market
is going to start to do this because
that single price is the true reflection
of the good faith and trust in the
United States. And as that yield goes
up, the very simple rubric is trust is
going down. Yield goes up, trust goes
down. The other thing that I would say
is this is happening at an incredibly
awkward moment, which is that we are
supposed to be in the middle of an
enormous financial buildout to support
AI. And if you go all the way back like
a hundred years, you know, the
industrial revolution, the grand
bargain, all of this stuff, the United
States government was the balance sheet,
right? They were the ones that were able
to step in. And unfortunately because if
it's financial situation the US
government is not able to do that.
That's why thank god we have companies
like Nvidia and Google and Microsoft and
Meta and Amazon who take on that burden.
And so I just wanted to tie it to this
other thing because there's so much
chirping by the way on the internet
about the balance sheet of Nvidia and
blah blah blah. And I think people
completely miss that these guys are
putting the entire US economy on their
back.
A hundred years ago, it would have been
the US government that did this. But the
US government is not in a position to do
it because Congress cannot get their act
together on spending. The president
actually has done something pretty
incredible, which is on the tail end of
those trade deals. If you guys remember,
he was able to find $2 trillion to pump
into the US economy to support this
buildup.
But the practical reality is that two
trillion comes from other nation states
and their processes are long and
meandering. So you have the situation
where all this money has to be invested.
It should be backs stop by the US
government. It's not in a financial
situation to do so. The president has
done some magic to try to relieve it in
the short term, but it's only a
short-term band-aid. The real solution,
as Freeberg says, is Congress needs to
come together and realize that they must
now fix this problem. Because if you see
yields, if you see the third year at 6%.
It is the beginning of a death spiral.
It's not going to be immediate, okay?
So, don't freak out, but it is the
beginning of some extreme pain. And that
pain will last years.
And the only thing that solves it now is
getting the budget under control, which
is a congressional act. It must happen.
Whether it's this year or the next year,
it just has to happen.
>> Saxs, the president was quite vocal
about cutting costs early on in the
presidency, but we haven't heard much
from the commander-in-chief about this.
Is the issue that no politician can
touch cutting spending? It's just too
toxic because Trump's in his final term.
He's lame duck by definition, right? is
the second and only term hopefully
unless he decides to take a third. Um,
but he hasn't been vocal about this. And
is it just too radioactive for anybody
in politics? And you got to spend a
little time. You dipped your toe there
in in DC. Is it just too toxic for
anybody to take on spending cuts? He
sent Elon in there. That was, you know,
pretty spicy. And it's obviously um not
occurring now. We're not cutting things
massively. in in fact this the debt's
going faster than it had started a year
ago. So what's your thought here Sax?
Give maybe you can move it out from just
Trump.
>> Yeah. Look, part of it is it is a
tragedy of the commons meaning you've
got 435 members of the house, 100
senators and they all get a vote and
then you've got the president and no one
of them controls the spending. In fact,
the spending the power of the purse
originates in the house and then goes
from there. So it is very very hard to
control spending when you have so many
people weighing in. If it was just, you
know, a couple of people getting
together in a room and sorting this out,
they probably could do it. But when so
many people have an incentive to
basically protect their programs, it
gets very, very hard. So that's the
tragedy of the commons part of it. And
the reality is the president doesn't
have a line item veto. It'd be great if
he did. He doesn't have the powers
constitutionally to completely reign
this in. And despite what the resistance
liberals say, he's not a king. I mean,
he doesn't have those kinds of powers.
That's basically the heart of the
problem. And you're right, he did back
Doge to the hilt. He's the only
president to ever back something like
that. And what happened? Elon got to the
point of cutting one agency or one sub
agency. And the hysteria was so great
that they accused him of killing
millions of children. It was total
nonsense. But Tesla dealerships were
getting firebombed. And that's the other
piece of this is how do you make reform?
How do you reform spending? How do you
rein it in when the media isn't on your
side and is not willing to report this
stuff accurately? That's the worst part
of it. I mean, the media, they don't
have an incentive politically to engage
in log rolling, but they do absolutely
nothing to report the story accurately.
I mean, just think about how the media
is reacting to all of that. So, it's
really a difficult problem when you
start off with the fact that no one
person controls it. you know, it really
is this tragedy of the commons and then
you don't have the media basically doing
a good job reporting this accurately. So
I, you know, I don't know how we get
reform on this and let me just say that
if if the Republicans lose control of
Congress, I don't think that's going to
make it better because you see now
>> that the political energy in the
Democrat party is all towards these
massive new spending programs that the
DSA wants. So, you know, if you vote for
quote unquote change by voting the
Democrats in, that's not going to help
either because again, they just want
more and more spending. So, I don't know
what the solution to this is.
>> Four, give us a timeline here.
Obviously, the Republicans love to cut
taxes. Um, and the Democrats love to
increase spending. And here we are. Uh,
this has not gotten better through three
or four presidents. The last person who
did this was I guess Clinton balanced
the budget, but this has been getting
worse and worse. At some point, we're
all in agreement. This is going to come
to due and we're going to have to have
some austerity measures. When does that
hit in your mind? Is there a breaking
point in terms of interest to GDP? Uh
maybe the people on the other side just
saying, "Hey, I want 12%." You guys have
bad debt. I want 12% on it. and we just
say we can't pay 12% and we just have to
go into full-on austerity measures. Is
there a breaking point? If so, when?
Well, the question is what does it break
to?
We
as a democracy
have this recursive solution
which is as the people feel some sort of
pain, they react with a vote.
This goes back to this point about do we
break for socialism because what ends up
happening post the midterms. So I think
sometime between 26 and the election
cycle in 28 the inflation problem and
remember the inflation problem is
fundamentally rooted in government
spending. So deficit spending is
correlated very nicely with the cost of
housing with the cost of healthare with
the cost of education and with the cost
of everything else. So the more the
government is spending on various
things, the the more expensive things
get. And so inflation is persistent
because what we thought were temporary
emergency stimulus measures during CO
very quickly got normalized and became
persistent spending cycles. You know, if
we went back to 2019, we would actually
have a budget surplus right now as a
country. Our economy has grown so much
since 2019 that if we had the same
spending levels as we had in 2019, our
federal government would be making a
profit paying down the debt. And the
reality is we've taken this emergency
spending and made it a permanent
spending. We did the same thing by the
way after the global financial crisis in
2008. There were some crazy stimulus
things that happened and we persisted
that spending. And so the question JakeL
is really like what happens next? So if
the inflation remains high, people's
affordability continues to go low,
they're going to vote for something
that's going to give them a solution.
And I don't see a political message
winning that says the federal government
will now spend less. We're going to cut
a bunch of stuff. So I worry that the
one-way solution here is something that
is very damaging to individual
liberties, to
a lot of the rights, a lot of the things
that make a free market work. and that
is some of these more kind of socialist
principles and socialist candidates
>> assets. I think that's kind of the
breaking point. So I think it's it's
more of like a you know spectrum and
then the reaction during that kind of
transition phase 26 to 28 can be
negative. Then the next big thing is
going to happen around 2030 to 2032. And
that's really where Social Security
doesn't have any money to pay anymore.
And I think during that era is also when
a lot of the states are going to become
bankrupt. We're not going to be able to
pay their obligations. And when the
states can't pay their obligations
around 2030 to 2032, you're going to
have both the Social Security bailout
and restructuring as well as the state
bailouts and restructuring. And that
might be the time that all of this stuff
breaks.
>> Wow. I mean, so you're saying we'll see
munis. Uh, yeah. And people will default
on their debt in the states. That would
be cataclysmic to have to bail out
something like California.
>> Well, because the obligations on the
unfunded pensions in the states are so
significant. And not to mention just the
debts. I mean, look, California's got
tens of billions of dollars spent on
this stupid railway that goes nowhere
where there's no tracks. And they're
talking political will to even stop
that. It' be the easiest cut in the
world.
>> Like, just think about the idiocy. Like
no one is saying we shouldn't do this.
Why is no one saying we shouldn't do
this?
>> That's what I'm saying about the media.
>> Trillion dollar.
Anybody who was in favor of a railway to
nowhere should just be shamed out of
existence.
>> Trillion dollars for a train from San
Francisco to Fresno that costs more than
an airline ticket is so idiotic. It's
like the movie Don't Look Up. Like look
up. This thing is absolutely ridiculous.
Turn this thing off. Why is no one even
just saying turn it off? It tells you
everything you need to know.
>> Private company built a Bright Line in
Florida and they seem to figure out how
to do it at a fraction of the price. So
like what are we even talking about
here? Like private industry, if this was
a good idea, would have built it. Yes,
Freedberg. Private industry would see an
opportunity and they would have built
it. There is no opportunity here.
>> Across the board, these government
programs cause more harm than good. When
the government intervenes in
underwriting student loans and gives
everyone a loan, administrative costs
went up by 6x and tuition skyrocketed 8%
a year, compounding for 30 years because
the government said we'll underwrite any
student loan. The same with housing and
now no young people can afford a house.
The same with health care where they
said we'll pay people to stay home and
not work to take care of people and we
won't check on whether or not they're
actually taking care of people. and the
cost of healthcare skyrocketed. You go
across every one of these government
programs and every one of them has the
adverse effect of driving up costs and
inflating everything. The core root of
inflation in this country. The core root
of it is government spending. And the
reason we are going to end up becoming a
socialist country is because we aren't
reigning in the government spending and
looking it in the mirror and saying,
"Guys, this is idiotic. What are we
doing?" And now the markets to Chamas's
point are telling us this is idiotic. We
are not going to underwrite this
anymore. And we need to have to
your point about media sacks 100 Nick
Shirley 60 Minutes whoever it is to just
say hey this spending this fraud is not
acceptable and we need to send people in
to go recapture that money. This is like
we're burning money that we don't the
fraud is layer one. There's like 18
layers to this. Layer one is fraud. Yes.
Of course. you know,
>> and given given the the tragedy of the
commons, the structural nature of it,
that there's no one person who's in
control of it, you need massive public
pressure to control it, and there's none
of that. And there's no effort to create
that public pressure by the mainstream
media. So, it's like, how do you even
get out of this? And
>> I don't think it happens that way. It
has to be an acute moment.
>> Yeah. You're saying there has to be a
crisis and then people react. But then
to Freeberg's point, we may get
socialism because people may not connect
what the real causes of the crisis are.
>> And Freeberg, that's my question for
you.
>> No, socialism is much more likely when
you know a 100 years ago when these
things are less interconnected. America
can't decide to do that. You understand
why? Because all of our debt is
interconnected to domestic actors,
international actors. It's not a
decision. There is no button you can
push to do that. And the reason is you
would go bankrupt overnight. So I think
the reality is that we will hit some
kind of a fiscal wall. Something will
get terribly broken and like in COVID or
like in GFC or like in 9/11, those are
the only moments where you can have
structural changes in expectations. The
structural changes that have had the
most impact on our lives happened in
these acute moments in 9/11, in GFC, and
in CO.
>> Yeah. And every one of them it ended up
becoming a never let a crisis go to
waste moment where it always argued in
favor of some big power by the
government.
>> What was your question for me?
>> Okay, so you think about like
affordability of houses, right? That
depends on mortgage rates. 30-year
mortgage right now I'm looking at the
average is 6.73%.
A little under 7%. It's about 150 basis
points above the 30-year Treasury,
right? So do you think the average
person can connect the dots here that
higher spending means higher treasury
rates which means higher mortgage rates
and that leads you to not be able to
afford the same level of house that you
would because your monthly payment is
much higher. I mean do people connect
those dots about what's happening?
>> No. No. But people want to blame
someone. Every time there's a crisis,
this group, even us, when we get
together on a podcast, something bad
happens. We always have this question,
who is to blame?
>> It's the first thing a human does.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> And literally the human that's human.
>> No, I mean that's the human brain.
That's how it works. It's like there's
some problem. Who do we blame? That's
the first thing you think about.
>> You you don't think you don't think
objectively what's the solution to the
problem? You think who do I blame?
That's the first thing you want to do.
And then the question is when mortgage
rates go up, who do you blame? The
current president, my congressman, blah
blah blah, reelect someone. That's the
response. And the person that shows up
and says, "I'm going to give you free
housing. I'm going to give you a free
bus. I'm going to give you free
mortgages. I'm going to take away the
the land from the landlord and give it
to you." You vote for that person. So, I
do worry that the the kind of
mechanistic response to what you're
describing, Sachs, which is a very
problematic situation for people, is the
lack of affordability of being able to
get a home, is give the keys of the
kingdom over to someone that's going to
put more fuel on the fire. And the fire
is government spending, and the fuel is
more government spending to try and
quote solve a problem that's caused by
the fire. And I think that's really
where I worry about this.
>> So, I think I know how we can blame
Daario.
>> Okay, circle it around. What did he do?
>> Here's the thing. Our only hope is AI,
right? Because only AI can create the
exponential growth necessary
>> Yes.
>> to make our economy grow big enough that
we can grow out of the problem.
>> Yes.
>> And if we hold back AI by creating some
new regulatory apparatus that takes
years to approve new model releases,
then we're cooked. Completely and Canada
and Putin. Those are the those are the
three people who are working.
>> I'm just I'm just kidding. Joking. We're
joking. Dario, come to
>> that. Is not Dario's fault. But anyway,
>> come to keep going.
>> No, seriously, come to summit. Listen, I
want to just people, we are kind of
counting on AI as the deos xmachina
to grow our way out of this thing. And
we really need I mean we need more
quarters like Nvidia and Salesforce just
posted. Like we need that to happen for
like 10 years to grow our way out of
this thing. One of the things that is a
great silver lining is that we're seeing
people migrate around the country or to
other countries as a way to vote against
outofc control spending. I lived in New
York, Los Angeles, and San Francisco.
And I did not appreciate how evil these
socialist and limousine liberals were
until I got to Texas. After a couple
years in Texas, I have seen what having
affordable homes does to a family, an
individual. You have people in those
cities who are so miserable because they
can't afford a home. They're paying
exorbitant rents and these people who
already own their, you know, Victorian
homes, etc. in San Francisco refuse to
build. And then in the great state of
Texas, if you look at this chart,
housing prices since the 2022 peak in
Austin are down, down, not up, sachs,
down 27%.
Since March of 2020, 25%. It can be
done. You need to have leadership that
says housing is a priority. Therefore,
we're going to let you build more
houses. It's being done in Texas, in
Florida. Those conservative, let the
free market work environments, let them
build the Bright Line. They have
high-speed trains going 125 mothering
hours uh miles per hour because they let
and they got out of the way and let
private industry figure out how to build
high-speed trains. This is a distinct
issue in certain groups where they want
to stop progress. They are deselling the
creation of homes. And when you get
homes, people feel great about their
lives. People in Texas are happy that
they have a home for $250,000.
They're everywhere. These things can be
solved. It just takes leadership. And
that's what we don't have is leaders
saying enough already. We're just going
to let people build more houses. All
right, let's keep moving through the
docket.
>> I love a good JCAL pmical. I'm just
pissed off about it because you
know
>> it's a total non sequator to
>> it is a nonsequator in some ways but you
know we're dancing around here who's
going to be the leader who will say
>> did you did you practice that before
>> no I didn't practice it I'm just
>> this just came to you at the top of your
head yes it's just another
>> yeah well actually I I hired Sax's
writer to do some uh punchups for me but
putting on the side it is obviously a
leadership issue that's too expensive
true
>> I'll get him a watch let's do a side
quest here. What did you think of Ducken
Miller writing his piece with AI and
getting busted and then the Wall Street
Journal saying, "Hey, it's totally
fine."
>> I thought that it was the left that
virtue signaled, but I I actually think
it's a class of people that virtue
signal.
>> Okay, here we go.
>> And they judge and they're judgmental
and they can't see the forest from the
trees. And this is probably they're like
the loudest chirpers in the peanut
gallery.
Stan Ducken Miller is the most
incredible investor of our generation.
Maybe, sorry, maybe like top three or
four.
>> He's up there. Yeah.
>> And so just shut the up and read what he
says. And you have an opinion and you're
like, "Oh my god, he has an M dash. Oh
my god, he used the AI flourish." It's
like you're missing the script. He's
telling you what's about to happen.
>> Sax, you agree? You think that the
opinion pieces in the Wall Street
Journal, New York Times should be
written by AI, not the person who puts
their name on still written by him. He
>> He didn't say it was written by him. He
admitted it's 100%.
>> He prompts He prompts it. He shapes it.
He guides it.
>> Yeah. A more precise way of putting it
is the take is his and then he uses the
AI to help him write it.
>> Look, I don't get all the pearl
clutching about this. I mean, you got to
be pretty dumb these days not to use AI
to help you write, and he's definitely
not dumb. This is his opinion. It's his
take. It's consistent with everything
he's been saying in the past for
decades. And in fact, the piece cites
the many times
>> and he's right.
>> Yeah. The piece mentions the many times
in the past he's weighed in on this.
>> I think that this clearly came from his
mind and he uses the AI to help him
write it.
>> The morons on X should be like, "Wait a
minute. How does this affect my company?
How does it affect my portfolio? How
will it affect my 401k? What will it do
to my parents' retirements? How should I
think about hedging this?" Instead of
that conversation,
all of you people were like, "Oh my god,
he had he was AI."
>> I think Jal, do you have a problem with
this? Are you one of the people who has
a problem?
>> I do think it's kind of the lip syncing
of uh writing as a writer. I find it
offensive to like let the system give
your entire opinion as opposed to using
it for research, which is totally fine.
Use it for proof reading, totally fine.
But to me, it feels like I went to see
Adele and she's lip-syncing. I really
want to hear him.
>> Don't use Excel. Only go to the guys
that use do hand calculations.
>> No, no, no. Here's the thing. I I would
rather he said the Dell saying Excel.
Don't use an Excel spreadsheet. I don't
trust those guys. I only trust the guys
that do the calculations by hand.
>> But if you were going to give your
opinion and it's not written by you, to
me, that is disappointing that it's not
disclosed. I think it's a much higher
standard to say, I'm going to write this
in my own voice. Sure, I could have
somebody who's a ghostriter help me
polish it. I could check my grammar with
it. I could do research with those are
all the valid uses, but I don't like
this idea that you're going to write
something in AI and then I read it and I
don't know. That to me feels icky and it
feels insincere. I would prefer people
just say upfront, I didn't write this,
but these are I'm kind of in agreement
with what the AI magic guessing word box
said. I find it personally offensive.
>> Yeah. Interesting opinion. May I
respond?
>> Sure. I was trying to get your opinion.
Go ahead.
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead. What do you think is the
difference between that concept and
having artists be required to disclose
whether or not they used Adobe Photoshop
and the very specific filters that they
used in Photoshop or DJs that use
specific software to use create
electronic music as opposed to doing
analog recordings of the music by hand
with guitars or people that for example
are using Microsoft Excel to create
spreadsheets as opposed to writing it
all down? Do I have to disclose that I
used Excel or that I used a calculator
or that I used a synthesizer or that I
used a Photoshop as opposed to doing it
in an analog way? At the end of the day,
digital tools for creativity and
creative output are done in parallel
with the human ingenuity. And the human
craft and the human creativity is
expressed, magnified, and in many cases
improved with digital tools. And the
definition of is someone quote using AI
is as nebulous as the rest of those
which is am I using quote AI to improve
my spelling to improve my grammar to
create novel sentences from scratch to
create novel paragraphs from scratch at
the end of the day if I give the AI a
whole bunch of inputs take the outputs
and edit that output am I quote using AI
this is I think one of the fundamental
issues is we treat AI as the standalone
simple kind of intelligence replacement
system and the heruristic is not
accurate with respect to how humans
actually use it and how it is like all
other tools a magnification of human
creativity, ingenuity and potential. Go
ahead.
>> The reason is the expectation of the
reader. The reader has a high
expectation and this is an important
issue and the reason why people were so
disappointed in this in a very large
way. It was not because they're virtue
signaling is because they actually care
about Stan's opinion and they want to
consume his opinion and make sure it's
not the AI slop opinion. That's why
people felt betrayed by what he did.
Now, this is a new
>> betrayed.
>> They I think they did. Yes. Because And
they also felt the Wall Street Journal
betrayed them because the Wall Street
Journal should be checking that anything
submitted is not AI slop. The same way
professors should be looking at students
work and making sure their papers are
not AI slop because we want them to have
learned something. And they want the
same thing when a teacher is teaching.
They people don't want to pay for a
teacher who uses AI slop either. And so
we as a society have to decide when do
we need it to come from the human and
understand it's 100% human or 60% human
and when do we think we trust the ayah
on it. I want to hear his actual
opinion.
>> I have questions. Many questions. Okay.
Question number one.
>> Are you suggesting that Stan didn't read
this thing that was generated or do you
think
>> I'm sure he did read it. Yes.
>> Okay. So it when he read it before
that's an open question. Did he
>> Okay. I think he Well, he defended it.
Yes, he read.
>> I hope he did.
>> Okay. So, you do you have an issue with
the fact that he read it, he thought,
"Yeah, this is what I think." Boom. And
hit the send button. That's a betrayal
to you.
>> I think not disclosing it is the
betrayal. If you want to write, if you
want to give me your opinion as
interpreted through the AI magic
guessing word box, you need to tell me.
>> I understand. I think it's difficult to
tell everybody.
>> I I understand. Now, I just want to
understand I'd like to make uh
>> Oh, listen. What exactly?
>> The standing disclosure for all future
publications that I put out, including
tweets, is that I try not to publish
anything without running it through AI
first to fact check it, to line edit it,
and to help me make the best argument I
can. So, this is a standing disclosure
that if I've written something and
published it, it's probably been through
AI.
>> I'm totally fine with moving. I'm
totally fine with proofing, to be clear.
Proofing, factecking, great uses of AI.
Grammar checker, great use of AI.
>> Now, you're debating the slider of how
much he proof checked he
>> two different things. I understand you
don't understand this concept because
you're not a trained journalist like I
am. But I can tell you there's a
distinct difference between being proof
read and having somebody plagiarize or
write some for you. And that's what this
is. And that's why people object.
>> Question. Is Stan Ducken Miller his next
oped? Is he allowed to use a computer?
>> Of course. Of course.
>> Okay. Okay. Okay. Let me keep going.
Yes.
>> Is he allowed to use a word processor or
is it just like the notepad?
>> I mean, you obviously understand he can
use any of those tools
he should disclose.
>> Wait, what about Grammarly? Is he
allowed to use Grammarly for
>> I encourage him to use Grammarly. I'm a
shareholder in Grammar Grammarly.
>> Jacob, what do you think his process was
on this post? Do you think that it was
simply delivered to him fully baked and
then he just said go with it or
>> that's what the AI detection software
said is that this is like 90% written by
AI. I'd be surprised if that was his
process. I My Here's my guess. This is
just a guess cuz I don't know. This is
just a guess. I don't know. My guess is
he had the take and he probably told the
AI the take either in writing or just
speaking to it or, you know, essentially
speaking to his assistant who basically
dictated it and put it in the AI and
then he probably got an output and he
probably made corrections and edits to
it and that was probably something like
his process. I don't really believe this
thing was just spit out as AI slop and
then he just said print it.
>> This is Jal's image of what happened.
He's sitting in his office in New York.
He gets in front of a browser. He opens
chat GPT and he writes yields up bad.
gets the whole thing printed out and
>> emails the opet
if you can't appreciate the lipsync must
have come from him.
>> If you can't if you can't appreciate the
lip-syncing analogy, it would
>> How do you lip sync?
>> Okay, here here's the problem with the
lip-sync analogy is he's criticizing
something that just happened.
>> It was this best and buyback policy,
right? He's criticizing his former
colleague about something very specific,
>> okay,
>> that the Secretary of the Treasury just
did. What's the lip-syncing? A lip-sync
is when you have a song that's been
performed a thousand times
>> there. This is novel and new.
>> Even more evidence of why he should
write it himself. It's really about the
you should respect the audience and not
to take the time to write it yourself,
not let the
I was part of the audience.
You can have the audience. That's a lot.
>> I I was like, "Oh, this is a useful data
point for me about
>> totally fine. Totally
>> a reminder."
>> Hey, listen. Some people
>> the the difficulties of yield. Wait, can
I ask you, did you read the article and
have an opinion about the substance of
it?
>> Yes. So, there was Well, I mean, I
wanted to know if they were coordinated
and this was some sort of like
Did you know it was AI generated before
someone printed that on this the
timeline that
>> No, it came up in my timeline first as
No, no, I didn't.
>> Exactly. I read it came up first. Hold
on. You asked me a question. Let me just
at least answer it.
>> It came up first. I saw the plagiarism,
the AI slop, whatever. Uh, as people
frame it in journal, that's how that's
that's how people
>> Let me tell you, I I read it. Hold on. I
read it when it first came out. I didn't
see the stuff in the timeline about the
software supposedly detecting it.
>> I got hit by the first.
>> It sounded completely consistent
with the many other times I have heard
Dr. Miller speak about the debt problem,
okay, on podcasts and written versions
or whatever. I didn't know. So, if he's
plagiarizing from someone, he's
plagiarizing himself.
>> Yeah. I mean, listen, plagiarism is not
the right analogy here. It's not perfect
because this is a new thing, but
>> it is taking credit for taking hold on,
let me finish. He's taking credit for
what the AI wrote. And I would prefer
him to take the time to respect the
audience, to write it himself because I
have respect for him and I want to
understand his true opinion, not as
interpreted through AI. Just like when I
hear somebody sing a song, I would like
to know that they don't autotune it and
they haven't post-produced it to the
point of absurdity. That's me. I believe
the artist should give you their actual
art, giving you their actual position
without using the eye. That's just my
opinion. Even the top performing even
the top performing artists use autotune
and like all these other tools to
basically make themselves sound the
best. And in a similar way here, we know
that AI gives people superpowers. Draen
Miller said, "I'm not the greatest
writer. What makes him interesting is
he's a thinker. He has a take. It's a
longheld position that he's had." And
he's willing to even criticize his
former colleague and I assume friend
because it violates, you know, his view
of the world. And he's saying he uses AI
to basically make his writing better. I
don't get it. I don't This is
>> I don't have a problem using Grammarly
type tool. I just don't like the idea
that it wrote it in full, which is what
the claim is. Now, we don't know. We'll
talk to Stan when he's at the event. I
will tell you, I prefer listening to a
band like Mark Knoffler where he
actually can write the song, play the
guitar riffs. I prefer that in my art or
in an opinion or in a novel to being
written by AI. That's my preference and
that was the expectation of the
audience. But this is a new
>> Now that you know Duck will continue to
use AI because he said it,
>> will you just ignore what he has to say?
>> No, I but I will not think as highly of
him and I don't think it's respecting.
>> So you're saying the substance of what
he says will no longer matter to you or
you're going to discount the substance
less.
>> You just said that. No, you just said
that you're going to discount the
substance hard for me. I will wonder. I
will wonder what is his actual opinion
constructed which came out of him
personally.
>> You're going to trust the greatest macro
trader in the world less tomorrow than
today because he used the tool to write
his
>> we're I I will wonder if it's actually
his opinion and how much work he did and
I feel it's disrespectful that he didn't
do it himself. That's how I feel. I will
wonder. It'll make me wonder if that is
actually his perfect opinion and crisply
his because I think he's phoning it in.
And I just don't like people phoning it
in. It's only 800 words. Write it
yourself. Work with a proof reader. It's
totally fine to do your research that
way. Listen, we're going to agree to
disagree on this one. CIA director made
an unannounced visit to Moscow. John
Ratcliffe made a surprise visit on
Tuesday and flew back the same day.
First visit by sitting CIA director
since November 2021. That was when Bill
Burns went to warn Putin not to invade
Ukraine. He invaded three months later.
Obviously, Wall Street Journal reporting
Ratcliffe was there to warn Russia to
not attack a NATO country. New US intel
reportedly shows Putin could be planning
to test NATO's resolve with a limited
assault in the next few years. Anything
from a cyber attack, small land
incursion, etc. Poly market says only
21% chance we get a Russian Ukraine
ceasefire by the end of the year.
Freeberg, you were on fire in the group
chat about this. What are your thoughts
of what's going on here?
>> There's wild speculation. Wall Street
Journal and others have reported that
the message that was delivered was don't
invade NATO
>> and don't use nukes on Ukraine. So,
there's been this kind of wild
speculation about what this means. It
just seemed like there's some meaningful
going on. But to Sax's point in our
group chat, this is speculation,
there's no evidence or Putin's made
>> and more than that. The president, I
think, called into a show to basically
say that that story was not true and the
contact was routine. And then the
Russian readout said roughly the same
thing. So, the truth is we don't know
what the meeting was about. Um, but
you know,
>> quite dramatic.
>> I think I think it's all speculation.
>> I I know what it was about. Oh, here we
go.
>> Drux's AI infused memo of the Wall
Street Journal.
>> Yes, he was warning he was warning Putin
to not use AI to write his next warning.
His next baby AI.
>> We flew over there to deliver a very
strict message which is we expect nonI
tool usage because we are journalists at
our core.
>> Yeah, I think it's possible, Jay Cal,
that the trained journalist got this one
wrong and we're engaging in wild
speculation and hyperbole. without
actually knowing what the meeting was
about.
>> Well, I mean, well, speculation is what
we do here. It's a podcast. Uh, that's
the whole point of the show is to
speculate what the hell's going on here.
>> First of all, both the American and the
Russian side have denied these dramatic
speculative claims that somehow
Rackcliffe was there to warn the
Russians not to invade Europe. I
actually believe those denials because
it wouldn't make sense for the Russians
to invade NATO countries. This is the
same kind of threat inflation that we've
heard for years from neocons about
Russia's supposedly imperial ambitions
to conquer all of Europe. There's simply
no basis for believing it. And frankly,
the war is not going badly for the
Russians. It's certainly taken a lot
longer than anyone thought. And Russia
has paid a heavy price in casualties. I
don't know that the numbers are what you
said, Freeberg, but I think if you look
at most of the sources now covering the
war, what they're saying is the Russians
are making slow but steady progress. And
it's Ukraine who is suffering the most.
First of all, the Russians have air
superiority. The Ukrainians are
basically out of air defense. So Kiev is
getting bombed on a routine basis. The
Russians are able to pretty much destroy
whatever they want at will. So the
Ukrainian infrastructure is paying a
heavy toll and this is coming on the eve
of what is expected to be you know a
pretty cold winter and Ukrainian power
is getting taken out. Moreover, Odessa
and the Black Sea ports of
Ukraine have been bombed and basically
shut down. So their economy is paying
this incredibly heavy price right now.
They're not able to export grain. So,
their economy is basically getting
destroyed and they're running out of
money. Zullinsky is running around
saying that he needs another $35 billion
or they're going to be out of money. The
US is not funding that, but he's trying
to get that from the Europeans. And then
their casualties, although we don't know
the numbers, are also huge. And now
there's been stories about them
potentially drafting women because
they're so low on soldiers. Keep in
mind, Russia has four or five times the
population of Ukraine. So they're able
to sustain much greater armies. So
things do not look great for Ukraine.
And frankly, Zalinsky should have
listened when President Trump told him,
"You don't have the cards in this war.
You should make a deal." Zinsky didn't
want to do that. He didn't want to make
a deal. He still doesn't want to make a
deal. He should make a deal. And um
frankly, I don't think Ukraine's going
to come out on top on this thing.
>> Chim, you have any thing you want to add
there or we'll just wrap? Yeah.
Thanks to Meta for solving my biggest
problem, which is imposing limits on
Instagram.
>> Yeah. Okay. We didn't even get to that
story. It's a big story.
>> I'm tired of playing whack-a-ole with my
kids and I can't do it. And they have
fake accounts and secret accounts and
this and that and yeah, please thank you
should have done it sooner, but I'm glad
you did it.
>> Yeah, I I will give them some amount of
credit for Yeah, they got drag kicking
and screaming to do the right thing, but
>> Tik Tok and YouTube I hope Tik Tok and
YouTube do the same thing. And uh it'll
it'll make the life of a parent
>> much simpler.
It'll allow us to actually parent versus
just policing device usage.
>> I'd love to see Android. And
>> it's exhausting being
a child with a device.
>> It's exhausting
>> and it's terrible for young women to be
on these Instagrams. We we we held the
line to 16 years old, but 17 we we lost
the battle. Where did you hold the line?
the kids for social media?
>> No, my kids aren't allowed until they're
16. But that's not the point. It's just
that look, we've talked about this. I've
been very consistent about this. This
could have happened a lot sooner. I'm
glad that it happened. I applaud Meta
for doing what they did. I hope that Tik
Tok and YouTube do the same thing. These
limitations are are coming around in
Australia, in Canada, and the UK.
They'll probably appear in other places.
It's physiologically and psychologically
really helpful for kids to have these
limits. So
>> yeah,
>> these parental control apps aren't that
great. They do a decent job. They don't
do a great job. So we're always on our
I'm always on my back foot as a parent
and it's frustrating and I would rather
just spend time with my kids on other
things other than screaming at them to
get off their phone.
>> Yeah, it's uh the tools are hard to
implement.
>> Hey Freeberg, what's going on with the
summit? how we deliver the summit.
>> Well, I'm excited to share with you that
the All-In Summit is just two weeks
away. This year, we've got some
incredible sponsors helping us bring
some big ideas to life. Iron is back as
the presenting sponsor of the All-In
Summit. Big thank you to our friends at
Iron.
>> Make sure you visit the Iron House at
Summit.
>> Always great time.
>> Make sure you visit the Iron House at
Summit. That's the on-site lounge where
you can kick back, relax, and hang out
between sessions. And new this year,
>> new,
>> you guys remember it from Napa, the
gifting boutique, brought to you by
merch.com. Every attendee fills a bag
with all-in merch,
>> plus special offers from sponsors. You
walk in, you walk out, you got a bag
full of goods, you're going to be very
happy. Oracle is back. They're bringing
an F1 racing simulator to the summit. If
you've ever wanted to know what it feels
like to take a corner at 180 miles an
hour, sort of like being in a debate
with JCAL here on the All-In Pod
>> without ending up in the hospital. This
is your chance. And EY is taking care of
business,
>> bringing their meeting pods, which is a
quiet space for folks to step out, take
a call, close a deal, do meetings, which
by the way happens a lot at the summit.
People are doing deals.
>> Just the tip of the iceberg. We've got
other major stuff happening from our
amazing sponsors. And just the tip, we
are keeping everything else under wraps.
More fun stuff coming.
>> We're excited. We will see you all at
the All-In Summit.
>> It's going to be a great party. Hey
Fred, what's going on with this cancer
vaccine and the stock that tripled in
the last two weeks? We didn't get to it
last week, but I know I want to hear
about it and I'm sure the audience does.
>> Yeah. Madna stock, I think, is what
you're talking about, right?
>> Yes. I think they went from like a 20
billion market cap to 60 billion market
cap on the positive readouts from this
thing that's being called a cancer
vaccine. And I think it's worth
highlighting how this cancer therapy
system works. This goes back to the '9s
where there was this idea that you could
create what are called neo antigens.
These are small peptides or proteins
that mimic a peptide or protein that's
unique to a cancer in your body. And so
that antigen, which means that your
immune system sees it as an invader,
causes your immune system to start to
make cells that destroy that protein.
And so by putting that protein in your
body, your immune system gets activated
and it gets turned on to go and find
that protein in other parts of your body
and destroy that protein. So the
objective is figure out what is the
protein that is unique to a particular
cancer, make that protein, stick it in
your body, and your immune system will
go and destroy the cancer that's in your
body. And so this imunotherapy, this
system of basically using an antigen
that's designed for a cancer in your
body to go and attack it, has been
around since, call it the late '9s. And
there was this big revolution in DNA
sequencing where we identified that we
could take samples of cancer,
put them in a DNA sequencer and look at
the sequence of the genes, the proteins
that are made because they're made from
genes that are unique to that particular
cancer and therefore make a personalized
neo antigen that's personalized to the
unique cancer that's in your body
because all these cancers mutate and
they're different and no two cancers are
identical. How do they get that key for
me personally versus you? How do you get
that information?
>> They would take a sample of of your your
tumor um or cancer cells. So when you
take your let's say you have you know a
melanoma and the reason that melanoma is
one of the kind of biggest targets for
this imunotherapy is that melanomas have
very kind of unique DNA mutations
because of UV light hitting the skin.
And so the particular cancer that you'll
get in a melanoma that you have is going
to be very unique with respect to the
rest of your body. It's going to be a
very unique mutation. So they take the a
little bit of the melanoma, they get the
DNA out of it, and when you do DNA
sequencing, you multiply the DNA by
millions or billions of times. You put
all that DNA in a DNA sequencer, it gets
chopped up and read. And then the
sequence data comes back and it says,
"This is what makes this cancer unique.
It's this little sequence of the DNA."
And that sequence of the DNA causes that
cancer to make a unique protein that is
basically like a key or an ID or
fingerprint of that cancer. They then
take that DNA and make protein from it.
Put that protein in your body and now
your immune system goes crazy and starts
attacking that protein because it's
like, oh, antigen, antigen, I got to go
get it. Now that those cells are
activated, those immune cells are
activated to that protein. They'll
eventually go destroy that cancer. So
this has been successful. There have
been hundreds of trials with this neo
antigen based therapy for many different
types of cancer and there's all these
trials that have tried to figure out
what's the right technique for
delivering the neo antigen. Do we make
the protein and then stick it in your
body or in this case with what madna did
make mrna and stick it in your body and
the mRNA causes your own cells to now
make that protein and spit it out ends
up in your blood and now your immune
cells got activated. So rather than
making the protein XVivo, which means
outside of your body, you're put making
the protein in your body in vivo and now
your body's making the protein. So the
the the idea with the mRNA concept is
you can get one shot, that shot goes
into your body, and now your body's
making that protein just like we made
the COVID vaccine.
>> Yes.
>> Your cells would make a particular
protein segment that would activate your
immune system and it would go kill that
cancer. There's other questions around
what are the other adgivants, what types
of cancer can you use this system for?
And then combination therapies. Are
there other cancer drugs that you can do
this in combination with? And the all
the trials that have been going on are
all about this delivery mechanism, the
technique that's used, the types of
cancer, the dosing, and getting all of
that stuff right. Now, what's
interesting about this is it is much
more of a technique than a drug in the
traditional sense.
>> It's a process of
>> it's a process, right? So the process
customized per person. So there's some
cost to doing it per person.
>> That's right. But the cost because I do
DNA sequencing at my company all day
long. Getting that sample very cheap.
Getting the DNA data very cheap.
Actually doing a lot of the upfront work
very cheap. Now theoretically making the
mRNA or making the protein should also
be pretty cheap, but it's human trials
and human safety. And so there's a lot
of questions around how do you make sure
that everything's safe and what's the
right combinations that people don't get
overreacted immune systems or that
people don't have adverse side effects.
So that's all of the tuning of this. But
I think what frustrates me the most
about all of this and everyone's kind of
lauding this as some unique breakthrough
and special and powerful and it's not
because a lot of people are going to
places like Montana and they are getting
peptides printed for their particular
cancer sequence and they are making
their own neo antigens putting it in
their body and getting cured of their
cancer. You can pay someone $50,000 to
do this for you today. There's a lot of
clinics that'll do it and it's not a
special FDA approved drug. To your
point, Jal, it's a process. The process
is take the DNA sequence from my cancer,
make a protein, put it back in my body,
my immune system goes and destroys the
cancer in my body. Great idea. So why is
Madna saying that they're going to
charge $500,000 for this? And that's
what I think frustrates me about all
this. Everyone's lauding this and
everyone's very happy about this, but
I'm actually pretty sad and frustrated
and disappointed by this. I don't think
that this technique which has been
largely developed through several
decades of iteration research and
development which was largely funded by
NIH and other public funding dollars
that has led to this incredible concept
of neo antigen amunotherapy for cancer
which can eradicate or theoretically
eliminate many different types of cancer
should now be patented FDA approved and
charged half a million dollars for
people to get treated for this.
>> Yeah. And so what I don't like about
this story is that a private
pharmaceutical company has seen their
market cap go from 20 billion to 60
billion cuz they went through this
regulatory process to create what in my
mind is a form of regulatory capture and
making the case that it's all about
safety and trials and we've got patents
and all this other stuff when
fundamentally there's an underlying
technique that was funded by a lot of
public research dollars that I think
should be more open- sourced, more
ubiquitous and every hospital should be
trained on how to do this process to
treat cancer patients should become much
more of a ubiquitous thing.
>> Do you think that people
>> I have two questions. We can end it on
that, but um do you think they're going
to be able to successfully defend this
patent uh in the United States and then
also globally because there's obviously
a global world here and people do travel
for treatments now. Medical tourism is a
thing. So if it's a half million dollars
here, can it be done for 50k in South
Korea, Japan, other places? Yeah. And
then secondies, whatever happened with
mRNA
and the COVID vaccine and a lot of the
concerns people had, we never got an
update on that, but obviously this
podcast started during all of that
>> and that was the first roll out if I at
scale. Correct. Uh for mRNA the
technology how do you feel? Yeah.
>> For years, Madna was working towards
this mRNA based cancer. They're calling
it a vaccine, but it's really
amunotherapy because a vaccine means you
prevent yourself from getting something.
Whereas in this case, you're actually
getting rid of something you already
have. So, I don't like the word vaccine.
But Madna worked on this for years and
they never really kind of got to market
with it and then co came about and they
pivoted very quickly and got this COVID
vaccine out. Madna has a whole bunch of
patents on the techniques and tools that
they use to make mRNA and to make sure
that it's not integrated into the the
human genome and it doesn't actually use
a traditional kind of replicating uh
system. So so you can't actually
replicate that mRNA which means it won't
start propagating in your body because
your cells typically might start making
copies of RNA if it ends up in your
cells. So there was a lot of stuff that
Madna developed that made their
particular mRNA technology patented and
safer and and so on. So I think that
they do have strong patent coverage on
their particular set of tools for mRNA.
But when I described earlier, so if I
take the sequence of your cancer cell
and I look at the DNA of it and I'm
like, I found what makes it unique.
There's this little sequence and now I
take that sequence of DNA and I can
stick it in a bacterial cell E.coli in a
little tank by what's called a
bioreactor and that bacterial cell will
now start to make that protein because
I've taken the DNA and put it in the
ecoli cell. So now the ecoli cell is
coding that DNA into RNA into proteins
because that's the sequence, right? DNA
turns into RNA turns into proteins. So
that E.coli cell, there's billions of
copies of those cells. They make
billions of copies of the protein. you
isolate the protein out of the
bioreactor and you can inject it into
your body. And when you inject that
protein into your body and now your
immune system gets activated. So you
don't necessarily need mRNA is my point.
>> And mRNA is a really effective way of
doing this. It's super cheap because you
don't have to go make all the protein
outside the body. You can literally just
print the mRNA and get one shot and
you're done.
>> But that endto-end system, the real cost
of doing that is very low. And so this
is one of those things where we have a
very big fundamental question that we
should all be asking which is like
should we be giving the monopoly on
cancer treatment to this company that
went through this FDA process and filed
a bunch of patents on certain techniques
but the general theory the general
thesis the general therapeutic process
is well described well understood
generally understood and should be
available everywhere and I think over
the next couple of years we are going to
see this cancer imunotherapy based
system start to proliferate
And you will see this happening overseas
very cheap. It is very efficacious and
we actually have a friend in common
who's kind of standing up a business to
do this in a very cheap way
>> up in Montana where you have a right to
try and they can make this stuff. So we
are going to see I think more of this
come to work. But it is for certain
types of cancer very efficacious, very
safe, very effective. So I I'm I'm
excited by this
>> requires just for people who are
listening who are normies. All of this
cancer treatment requires early
detection and that's something that
people have been working on with the
blood test, a galleria, I believe it's
called. So getting to the cancer and
getting regularly tested is a critical
part of this. Yes.
>> So you're talking about a gallery test
by grail.
>> The blood test. Yeah,
>> the blood test. Yeah.
>> Just early testing is the key piece for
all of us to keep in mind. get tested
early and often for cancer.
>> Yeah. And and remember there's a bunch
of these new what are called modalities,
new modes of therapy, therapeutic
modalities that are being used to
destroy cancer. One was carti therapy
where you take tea cells out of your
body
>> and you use crisper or some other system
to reprogram those tea cells to go after
remember that protein I described. So
you actually program the tea cells to go
find a specific protein in your body and
destroy it. So they go find the protein
that's unique to a specific type of
cancer cell and the tea cells get put
back in your body and they destroy it.
CARTT therapy. CARTT therapy costs a
million dollars. And for people with
blood cancers where the cancer cells
aren't clumped together in a tumor um
but blood cancers, the cancer cells
float around individually in the blood.
And so by putting tea cells in your
blood, it's very easy or it's much
easier for the te- cells to find the
cancer cell, grab them, and destroy
them. And so for blood cancers like
multiple myyoma, the efficacy is
incredible with CRT therapies now. So
that's a new type of modality, this is a
new type of modality um this uh mRNA or
neo antigen therapy. So there's all
these new techniques that are being used
to destroy cancer and I think in
aggregate we should be very excited and
optimistic about where this is headed.
>> Wow. Thanks for sharing and uh let's
hope for the best with implementing
this. And I love this right to try. That
seems to be something we should talk
about in a future episode. We'll see you
all next time on the podcast. Bye-bye.
>> Bye-bye.
>> We'll let your winners ride.
>> Rain.
>> We open sourced it to the fans and
they've just gone crazy with it.
>> Love you. Queen of kinshine
besties are gone.
>> That is my dog taking notice your
driveways.
>> Oh man, my appetiter will meet up.
>> We should all just get a room and just
have one big huge orgy cuz they're all
just useless. It's like this like sexual
tension that we just need to release
somehow.
>> Wet your feet. Wet your feet. her feet.
>> We need to get Mercury's back.
I'm going all in.